whattalking.com 2015-09-30

# Privacy

Whattalking . com – Privacy policy

whattalking.com respects the privacy of users and is committed to protect their privacy in all respects. Should you have any questions concerning this privacy policy, please email us at jodhana@gmail.com.

The present privacy policy governs the online information collection practices of whattalking.com ("we" or "us" or "whattalking.com"). Specifically, it outlines the types of information that we gather about you from your use of the whattalking.com website (the "Site"), and the ways in which we use and don’t use this information. This privacy policy, including our children’s privacy statement, does not apply to any information you may provide to us or that we may collect offline and/or through other means. To register for full access to the Site and in certain areas of the Site (for example, on contest entry pages), where personal information is requested, you may be asked for your age or birth date. You hereby agree that all information you provide to whattalking.com regarding age verification shall be truthful, accurate, and complete.

This privacy policy details important information regarding the use and disclosure of user and/ or member information collected on the Site. whattalking.com provides this privacy policy to help you make an informed decision about whether to use or discontinue using the Site.

This privacy policy is incorporated into and is subject to the whattalking.com Terms of Use. Your use of the whattalking.com Site and any personal information you provide on the Site remains subject to the terms of this privacy policy and our Terms of Use.

Please note that any video, image, comment or other content posted on the Site becomes published content and is not considered personally identifiable information which is subject to this privacy notice.

Please read this privacy policy carefully. By visiting and using the Site, you agree that your use of the Site, and any dispute over privacy, is governed by this privacy policy and our Terms of Use at the following link: Terms of Use.

WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED ABOUT OUR USERS AND MEMBERS?

The information that we collect about you while you are using the Site falls into the following general categories:

1\. User provided information: We may collect and store information, personal or otherwise, that you voluntarily supply either while on the Site or in responding via email in connection with a feature provided on the Site. Some examples of this type of information include demographic information that you electronically submit when you sign up for access to certain features on the Site, information (such as your name or email address) that you electronically submit when you register for surveys or contests on the Site, information that you post on message boards on the Site, and information contained in search requests or questions that you submit to the Site. If you decline to supply or provide us with certain information while using the Site, you may not be able to use or participate in some or all of the features offered through the Site.

2\. Cookies information: When you visit the whattalking.com Site, we may send one or more cookies – a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. whattalking.com use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser help file directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the whattalking.com Site may not function properly.

In addition, third party advertisers or third party ad servers that place and present advertising on the Site also may collect information from you via cookies, web beacons, clear .gifs or similar technologies. These third party advertisers and ad servers may use the information they collect to help present their advertisements, to help measure and research the advertisements’ effectiveness, or for other uses. The use and collection of your information by these third party advertisers and ad servers is governed by the relevant third party’s privacy policy and is not covered by our privacy policy. Indeed, the privacy policy of these third party advertisers and ad servers may be different from our privacy policy.

3\. Log file information: When you use the whattalking.com Site, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser language, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform type, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.

4\. Clear / transparent GIFs information: When you use the whattalking.com Site, we may employ "clear GIFs" (a.k.a. Web Beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns of our users / members anonymously. In addition, we may also use clear GIFs in HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients.

HOW IS THIS INFORMATION USED?

1\. If you submit personally identifiable information to us through the whattalking.com Site, then we use your personal information to operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the whattalking.com Site.

2\. Any personal information or video content that you voluntarily disclose online (on discussion boards, in messages and chat areas, within your public profile page, etc.) becomes publicly available and can be collected, seen and used by others besides us. We cannot be and are not responsible for any unauthorized third party use of such information. Your account name (not your email address) is displayed to other users / members when you upload videos or send messages through the whattalking.com Site and other users / members can contact you through messages and comments. Any videos that you submit to the whattalking.com Site may be redistributed through the internet and other media channels, and may be viewed by the general public.

3\. We do not use your email address or other personally identifiable information to send commercial or marketing messages without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in or opt-out. We may provide our advertisers with information about you and other visitors that will enable our advertisers to better target ads to specific types of visitors. We reserve the right to use and to disclose to third parties all of the information that we collect online about you and other visitors in any way and for any purpose, with one important exception viz. We will not use the information that we collect online from you while you are using the Site, nor will we authorize third parties to use such information, to mail or email promotional offers directly to you unless you have specifically informed us that you would like to receive promotional offers from us and/or from third parties. If you choose to receive these promotional offers, then your information may be used for direct mail or email marketing. We may, however, use your email address without further consent for non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major whattalking.com Site changes or for customer service purposes).

4\. We use both your personally identifiable information and certain non-personally-identifiable information (such as anonymous user usage data, cookies, IP addresses, browser type, click stream data, etc.) to improve the quality and design of the whattalking.com Site and to create new features, promotions, functionality, and services by storing, tracking, and analyzing user / member preferences and trends.

5\. We use cookies, clear gifs, and log file information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the whattalking.com Site; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, pages viewed, etc.; and (e) track your entries, submissions, and status in promotions, and contests.

6\. The Site includes links to other websites and provides access to products and services offered by third parties, whose privacy policies we do not control. When you access another website or purchase third party products or services through the Site, use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting or the provider of such products or services.

7\. We may also make some content, products and services available through our Site through cooperative relationships with third party providers, where the brands of our provider partner appear on the Site in connection with such content, products and/or services. We may share with our provider partner any information you provide, or that is collected, in the course of visiting any pages that are made available in cooperation with our provider partner. In some cases, the provider partner may collect information from you directly; in which cases the privacy policy of the provider partner may apply to the provider partner’s use of your information. The privacy policy of our provider partners may differ from ours. If you have any questions regarding the privacy policy of one of our provider partners, you should contact the provider partner directly for more information. Be aware that we may occasionally release information about visitors / members when release is appropriate to comply with law, to enforce our [ Terms of Service ](http://www.adtan.com/terms-of-service/) agreement, or to protect the rights, property or safety of users of the Site, the public, or the whattalking.com Site.

WHEN whattalking.com DISCLOSES INFORMATION

We provide personally identifiable information and non-personally-identifiable information to our subsidiaries, affiliate companies, or other businesses or people for the purpose of processing such information on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process such information in compliance with our privacy policy, and we use reasonable efforts to limit their use of such information and to use other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

We do share non-personally-identifiable information (such as anonymous User usage data, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third-parties to assist them in understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the whattalking.com Site.

We may release personally identifiable information and/or non-personally-identifiable information if required to do so by law, or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with any law or to respond to a court order or an order from any governing body or statutory authority.

whattalking.com also reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information and/or non-personally-identifiable information that whattalking.com believes, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to enforce our Terms of Use, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend itself against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, to protect the security or integrity of our web site, and to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of whattalking.com, our users / members or others.

INVITATIONS AND OTHER COMMUNICATIONS TO NON-MEMBERS

whattalking.com members can invite friends to join the service by sending invitation emails via our automated invitation system. The whattalking.com Site stores the email addresses that members provide so that the respondents may be added to the friend’s list of the member sending the invitations, and also to send reminders of the invitations. The whattalking.com Site does not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations, invitation reminders (up to three (3) per email address). Recipients of invitations from whattalking.com may contact the whattalking.com Site to request the removal of their information from our database.

whattalking.com members may also store email addresses of people they know in their internal whattalking.com address book and may also choose to send invitations and other communications to those addresses. You may prevent email invitations from us by sending a single email with the subject "BLOCK" to jodhana@gmail.com. Please note that the email must come from the account you wish to block.

OUR COMMITMENT TO CHILDRENS’ PRIVACY

The Site is NOT directed to or intended for people under the age of eighteen. A User less than 18 (Eighteen) years of age should not register to use the Site. whattalking.com do not knowingly collect any personal information from people under the age of eighteen. If you are a parent of a child under the age of eighteen and you have questions about our Site or Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact the whattalking.com Privacy Coordinator at Privacy Policy.

OUR COMMITMENT TO DATA SECURITY

We use commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to whattalking.com and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, whattalking.com makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

If whattalking.com learn of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. whattalking.com may post a notice on the whattalking.com Site if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive a free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us using this link Privacy Policy.

SPECIAL NOTE TO INTERNATIONAL USERS / MEMBERS

whattalking.com is hosted in India and is intended for and directed to users / members in India. If you are a user / member accessing the whattalking.com Site from any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, protection and disclosure, that differ from Indian laws, please be advised that through your use of the whattalking.com Site, this Privacy Notice, and our Terms of Use, you are transferring your personal information to India and you consent to that transfer. We will only be complying with the legal provisions on the subject matter as applicable in India from time to time.

HOW YOU CAN MAKE CHANGES TO YOUR INFORMATION NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES: We reserve the right at any time to: change the terms of this Agreement; change the Services, including eliminating or modifying any content on or feature of the Site; or change/charge any fees or charges for use of the Services. Any changes we make will be effective immediately on notice, which we may give either by posting the new Agreement on the Site or via electronic mail. Your use of the Services after such notice will be deemed acceptance of such changes. Be sure to review this Agreement periodically to ensure your familiarity with the most current version. You will always be able to tell when the version was last updated by checking the "Last Revised" date in the header of this agreement.

CONFLICT RESOLUTION: We are committed to resolving disputes as soon as feasible and shall endeavor to resolve all disputes brought to our notice in keeping with the mechanism prescribed, within 30 working days of such receipt.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [ click here ](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. 

Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. 

Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [ Google ad and content network privacy policy ](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

CONTACT INFORMATION If site users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please [ contact us ](http://www.adtan.com/contact-us/) at: E-mail: jodhana@gmail.com
